# Kari McCullough

Benicia, Ca, USA • Open to Remote • 415-935-0840 • design@thekarinoelle.com

www.thekarinoelle.com • behance.net/thekarinoelle • linkedin.com/in/thekarinoelle



Experienced improviser becomes UX/UI Designer. How do improv skills transfer over to design? Glad you asked. An improviser needs to actively listen to their scene partner to build an enjoyable scene for the audience, the same way a UX/UI Designer listens and empathizes with users to produce the best possible solutions for an enjoyable product.

## **Projects**

WatchGuide: designed a native streaming app for iOS and Android by performing a competitor analysis, designing user flows, wireframing, prototyping, and usability testing using Figma.

Tasty Vegan: created a responsive vegan recipe web app by conducting user research, creating user personas, defining MVP, user flows and wireframing, prototyping, usability testing, and creating style guides using Adobe XD.

Portfolio Website: developed a portfolio website by curating design projects, designing a color palette, and usability testing using Figma, Atom, Github, HTML, CSS, and Javascript.

## **Recent Work Experience**

#### Soccer Coach

Girls Leading Girls, San Francisco, Ca, 2019-Present

Prototyped an animation of a new soccer training exercise using Figma to share with a coaching staff who require visual aid for clearer communication, resulting in staff satisfaction with the visual aid and efficient use of practice time.

Formed a new exercise combining basic soccer training and an improv game to build a healthy group dynamic for a newly formed team of players, increasing their morale and participation by 150%.

#### Administrator and Instructor

Endgames Improv, San Francisco, Ca, 2017–2020

Took on multiple roles for an expanding community interest company with various departments and no manager. Helped to open communication between teams to increase productivity and reduce stress and frustration among employees.

Created and tested a web app prototype using AppSheet to reduce employee time-tracking errors and administration overhead, resulting in the company adopting the clocking system into its standard operating procedures and employee satisfaction.

## **Skills**

Mobile app design
Figma, Adobe XD, Sketch
Adobe Photoshop
Working knowledge of HTML,
CSS, Atom, Github
Basics of JavaScript
Final Cut Pro

## My Specialties

User Research



User Flows



## Interface Design



#### Wireframing & Prototypes



## **Education**

Career Foundry UI Design Certification 2020-2021

East Carolina University Theater Arts 82 units towards BA